# TOMMASO INNOCENTI

+1 857-928-9979 | innocenti.t@northeastern.edu | linkedin.com/in/innotommy| github.com/innotommy https://innotommy.com| Boston (MA)

### Research Overview

My research focuses on Security and Privacy to increase the security of general users. My works reflect my passion and tenacity to investigate complex security problems. With my research, I increased the security of the Best Current Practice of OAuth and the OpenID protocol. Various topics in Web Security attract my interest, but the current focal point of my research is Web Authentication.

### **EDUCATION**

Ph.D. Computer Science | CybersecuritySep. 2018 – (Expected Sep. 2024)Northeastern University | GPA: 4.0/4.0Boston, USAMaster in Computer Science And EngineeringSep. 2014 – May 2018Politecnico di Milano | Grade: 101/110Milano, ItalyErasmus ExperienceSep. 2015 – Feb. 2016Universidad Complutense de Madrid (UCM)Madrid, Spain

### WORK EXPERIENCE

LEADERs Program Spring 2020 – (ongoing)

Gordon Institute of Engineering Leadership | Northeastern University

Boston, USA

• Applied experiential learning initiative that integrates leadership and professional-skills education with a research project

Research Assistant Apr. 2018 – Sep. 2018

Northeastern University

Boston, USA

- Manage a research topic in a team environment
- Performed cutting edge security research

Master Thesis at SecLab Nov. 2016 – June 2017

Less is more (Secure): automated reduction of the attack surface in modern Browser

Boston, USA

- Investigated the Browser functionalities as potential attack surface
- Instrumented the Browser functionalities to define the minimal set of required functionality
- Evaluated the model extracted against: reduction of Attack surface and the performance increase

### PROJECTS AND RESEARCH

DIMVA'21 | (A.R. 16/66 = 28.7%)

# OAuth 2.0 Redirect URI Validation Falls Short, Literally Tommaso Innocenti, Matteo Golinelli, Ali Mirheidari, Kaan Onarlioglu, Bruno Crispo, Engin Kirda ACSAC'23 | (A.R. 59/246 = 23.9%) FRAMESHIFTER: Security Implications of HTTP/2-to-HTTP/1 Conversion Anomalies Bahruz Jabiyev, Steven Sprecher, Anthony Gavazzi, Tommaso Innocenti, Kaan Onarlioglu, Engin Kirda USENIX'22 | (A.R. 392/2535 = 15.4%) You've Got (a Reset) Mail: A Security Analysis of Email-Based Password Reset Procedures Sum 2021 Tommaso Innocenti, Ali Mirheidari, Amin Kharraz, Bruno Crispo, Engin Kirda Virtual

# CONFERENCES AND PRESENTATIONS

Annual Computer Security Applications Conference (ACSAC)'23	December 2023
OAuth 2.0 Redirect URI Validation Falls Short, Literally	Austin, Texas
OAuth Security Workshop (OSW)'23	August 2023
OAuth 2.0 Redirect URI Validation Falls Short, Literally	Royal Holloway University, London
Federal Trade Commission (FTC) invited talk	October 2021
You've Got (a Reset) Mail: A Security Analysis of Email-Based Password Rese	t Procedures Virtual
Detection of Intrusions and Malware & Vulnerability Assessment (DIMVA)'21 July	
You've Got (a Reset) Mail: A Security Analysis of Email-Based Password Rese	t Procedures Virtual

## PROFESSIONAL SERVICES/NETWORK

OpenID foundation October 2023

Conformance-suite

IETF OAuth Working Group October 2023

OAuth 2.0 Security Best Current Practice

Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS)'23

November 2022

Sub-reviewer Copenhagen, Denmark
USENIX'23 August 2022
Sub-reviewer Anaheim, California

SELECTED ACHIEVEMENT/ GRANTS

Annual Computer Security Applications Conference (ACSAC)'23 December 2023

Travel grant Austin, Texas

OAuth Security Workshop (OSW)'23 August 2023

Student scholarship London, United Kingdom

Erasmus+ Sep. 2015 Feb. 2016

Exchange program Complutense University of Madrid

SKILLS

**Languages**: English C1 (TOEFL score:100/120), Spanish A1, Italian (mother tongue)

Programming: C, Java, C++, Python, SQL, HTML, Node.js, Puppeteer, JavaScript, Docker, Git

**Document Creation**: Microsoft Office Suite, LaTex